<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events-rsses on Think-Release</title>
    <link>https://esaezgil.github.io/events/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events-rsses on Think-Release</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 18:04:04 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://esaezgil.github.io/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>THack Mallorca - May&#39;16</title>
      <link>https://esaezgil.github.io/events/thackmallorca16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 18:04:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esaezgil.github.io/events/thackmallorca16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During Friday night May 6 through Sunday May 8 I attended &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tnooz.com/event/thack-mallorca-2016/&#34;&gt;THack Mallorca&lt;/a&gt;, a Hackathon organized by &lt;a href=&#34;https://tnooz.com&#34;&gt;Tnooz&lt;/a&gt; a global provider of news and analysis to the travel industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the weekend I worked almost non-stop in a 4 people team: 2 developers from &lt;a href=&#34;http://minube.com&#34;&gt;minube&lt;/a&gt; and 2 developers from &lt;a href=&#34;http://skyscanner.net&#34;&gt;Skyscanner&lt;/a&gt; including myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After discussing different sort of ideas during a quick brain storming session, we agreed on creating a new product targeting travelers who prioritize activities over sightseeing. We also tried to maximize our ROI by consuming three external APIs from different sponsors. The team developed an internal API that suggested the best hotel based on the location of the activities chosen by the user and I developed an Android app consuming the team&amp;rsquo;s API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, it was a great but exhausting experience in terms of working in an extremely fast paced environment and collaborating with other developers inmersed in the travel industry. We also had the chance to talk to many competing teams composed of people coming from other companies like Trivago or Viajes el Corte Ingles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These events are quite refreshing as it allows to somehow blur the self-imposed limitations that are inherent to working in big companies with clear goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a great and nice surprise to win 3 prizes from 3 different sponsors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second prize from &lt;a href=&#34;http://hotelbeds.com&#34;&gt;HotelBeds&lt;/a&gt; for best use of their API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second prize from &lt;a href=&#34;http://musement.com&#34;&gt;Musement&lt;/a&gt; for best use of their API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First prize from &lt;a href=&#34;http://booking.com&#34;&gt;Booking.com&lt;/a&gt; for best API feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check the presentation we did for the final pitch:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async class=&#39;speakerdeck-embed&#39; data-id=&#39;f96342f403e34a488e49bf296bbc1581&#39; data-ratio=&#39;1.33333333333333&#39; src=&#39;//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a great time during this event and would gladly join again in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>