<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events-rsses on Think-Release</title>
    <link>https://esaezgil.github.io/events/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events-rsses on Think-Release</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 18:34:25 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://esaezgil.github.io/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>HackUPC 2016</title>
      <link>https://esaezgil.github.io/events/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 18:34:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esaezgil.github.io/events/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hackupc.com/&#34;&gt;HackUPC&lt;/a&gt; is a student-led and student-oriented hackathon for tech-enthusiast held in Barcelona, at the premises of Universidad Politecnica de Catalunya over the weekend of October 1st 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time I attended the event as a company representative for &lt;a href=&#34;http://skyscanner.net&#34;&gt;Skyscanner&lt;/a&gt;, the main sponsor of the event. The hackathon gathered 500 students from all over the world and was an inmense success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my 4th Hackathon over the last year but my first one as a sponsor and not a participant. Therefore, the event gave me the opportunity to gain a different insight for this kind of events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent about 18 hours at the event during weekend with the goal of helping participants make the most out of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.business.skyscanner.net/&#34;&gt;Skyscanner API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quality of the submissions was astonishing. It is quite refreshing to see how much can be achieved over a weekend of intense work and collaboration. The projects submitted making use of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://skyscanner.net&#34;&gt;Skyscanner&lt;/a&gt; API are posted &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackupc2016f.devpost.com/submissions/search?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;prize_filter%5Bprizes%5D%5B%5D=12500&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favourite momments during the Hackathon was the &amp;lsquo;Science Fair&amp;rsquo; demos at the end of the event. As part of the judging panel for the Skyscanner prizes I got to know the motivations behind the projects that were crafted during the weekend and learnt more about the rapid prototyping techniques and technologies that hackers made use of to create an MVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I had the chance to deliver [a short talk]() at the end of the event where I encouraged attendees to apply for a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.skyscanner.net/jobs/&#34;&gt;position at Skyscanner&lt;/a&gt; after talking with them over the weekend about company culture and mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Code or ping-pong? Both at &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/hackupc?src=hash&#34;&gt;#hackupc&lt;/a&gt; Join us! &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/skyscanner?src=hash&#34;&gt;#skyscanner&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/barcelona?src=hash&#34;&gt;#barcelona&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/N69diMVcn7&#34;&gt;https://t.co/N69diMVcn7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Enrique (@eqirn) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/eqirn/status/784503844839497728&#34;&gt;October 7, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, attending this event as a sponsor was a really good experience.
Looking forward to attend another hackathon soon enough!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THack Mallorca - May&#39;16</title>
      <link>https://esaezgil.github.io/events/thackmallorca16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 18:04:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esaezgil.github.io/events/thackmallorca16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During Friday night May 6 through Sunday May 8 I attended &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tnooz.com/event/thack-mallorca-2016/&#34;&gt;THack Mallorca&lt;/a&gt;, a Hackathon organized by &lt;a href=&#34;https://tnooz.com&#34;&gt;Tnooz&lt;/a&gt; a global provider of news and analysis to the travel industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the weekend I worked almost non-stop in a 4 people team: 2 developers from &lt;a href=&#34;http://minube.com&#34;&gt;minube&lt;/a&gt; and 2 developers from &lt;a href=&#34;http://skyscanner.net&#34;&gt;Skyscanner&lt;/a&gt; including myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After discussing different sort of ideas during a quick brain storming session, we agreed on creating a new product targeting travelers who prioritize activities over sightseeing. We also tried to maximize our ROI by consuming three external APIs from different sponsors. The team developed an internal API that suggested the best hotel based on the location of the activities chosen by the user and I developed an Android app consuming the team&amp;rsquo;s API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, it was a great but exhausting experience in terms of working in an extremely fast paced environment and collaborating with other developers inmersed in the travel industry. We also had the chance to talk to many competing teams composed of people coming from other companies like Trivago or Viajes el Corte Ingles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These events are quite refreshing as it allows to somehow blur the self-imposed limitations that are inherent to working in big companies with clear goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a great and nice surprise to win 3 prizes from 3 different sponsors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second prize from &lt;a href=&#34;http://hotelbeds.com&#34;&gt;HotelBeds&lt;/a&gt; for best use of their API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second prize from &lt;a href=&#34;http://musement.com&#34;&gt;Musement&lt;/a&gt; for best use of their API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First prize from &lt;a href=&#34;http://booking.com&#34;&gt;Booking.com&lt;/a&gt; for best API feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check the presentation we did for the final pitch:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async class=&#39;speakerdeck-embed&#39; data-id=&#39;f96342f403e34a488e49bf296bbc1581&#39; data-ratio=&#39;1.33333333333333&#39; src=&#39;//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js&#39;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a great time during this event and would gladly join again in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>